manning.com 2019-03-30

# Manning | Privacy

## Manning privacy policy

This statement concerns our policy regarding the personal information that we may gather from visitors to our Web sites (all manning.com, [manning-sandbox.com](http://www.manning-sandbox.com/) and [manning-source.com](http://www.manning-source.com/)) or from customers who buy directly from us. It lets you know why we collect information and the things that you can do to control it.

## Why we collect personal information

Manning collects personal information so that we can keep our readers informed. We use the data to let you know about recent news, upcoming release dates, special offers, events and the like that our customers might wish to hear about. We also collect anonymous information about how visitors make use of our website, in order to analyze and improve the user experience.

## The information Manning gathers and tracks

Manning collects two types of information: 1) data that is submitted voluntarily by visitors wishing to receive news or product information, to provide us with feedback or to purchase products directly from us; and 2) aggregated tracking data that we gather while users are interacting with our Web sites.

Manning never sells or rents email addresses or other personally identifiable information that visitors provide. We will, however, release information in order to comply with the law, or when it is appropriate to protect the rights, property or safety of Manning, our users, or others. It may be necessary for Manning to exchange information with other companies or agencies in the interest of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

## Tracking information

Manning tracks such information as clickstreams, click-throughs, pageviews, and search terms in order to analyze cumulative website usage. This traffic and demographic data is completely anonymous, is not analyzed or stored in a manner which identifies individual users, and is for internal use only. We do not share this information with any third parties, ever.

## Cookies

Manning uses small data files called cookies to help us tailor our websites to individual users. Cookies are transferred to your computer's hard drive through your web browser, and then enable our systems to recognize our users' computers and to track user traffic patterns.

Additionally, Manning's shopping cart currently requires the use of third party cookies. These cookies are used only for tracking contents (products) added to your Aabaco e-commerce shopping cart from our website. We are currently evaluating alternative solutions for this feature and hope to remove the need for third party cookies in the near future.

## Notification of changes

This policy was put in effect on September 21, 2005.

If we revise our Privacy Policy, we will post any changes on manning.com. Should we wish to use personally identifiable information for a different purpose than was stated at the time it was collected, we will send users notice via email and give them the choice of opting-out of any new use of their personal information.

## How to update, correct, or delete your information

To make changes or to unsubscribe from our email newsletters or product announcements, please send an email to the Manning Marketing Department at [mkt@manning.com](mailto:mkt@manning.com).
